------------------OP-----------------------------
------------------ED-----------------------------
---------------------------------------------------------------------
あのね
つまり、自信がないのね
季節感無視した内容でしたけど
だって、負けたら立ち直れないじゃないですか
物すごく丁寧なお弁当だったんですよ
樱律联萌站 http://bbs.ylbud.com/
樱律联萌站为您带来高质量中日双语字幕
中日双语字幕由 樱律字幕组 制作
感谢以下成员倾情制作
听译：五月、吉禾　校对：jez　时间轴：咲夜　后期：OMG
So basically, you're feeling unconfident.
それに、ほら
Because if I lose, I'll never be able to recover.
もし毒入りだったら
真奥さん達危ないかも
Villa Rosa
Sasazuka
Okay, look...
It was completely seasonally inappropriate,
エンテイスラの刺客なら
but it was still a really well-done lunch box!
もうかたはついてるわね
はい
A-And Mr. Maou and the others could be
in danger if she poisoned it, you know?
千穂ちゃん
取ってつけたように私達より理由にしないて
正面からぶつかりなさい
If she's an Ente Isla assassin,
the job's already done.
はい
Yes.
Chiho, don't use us as a
lame excuse. Go at this head-on.
はい、ただいま
おや、貞夫殿、お客人が
R-Right...
ちょっと待って
ささささささささ、貞夫？
Coming!
千穂ちゃん
My goodness.
Good Sadao, you have a visitor.
- 'Kay, hold on a sec. Who is it? The MHK?
- S-S-S-S-S-S-S-S-Sadao?
- No, it's the good Emi.
- Chiho?!
- Again?!
- S-S-S-S-S-Sadao?
この瞬間
在这瞬间
この場所がスダート
这里就是起点
イメージして見よう
试着想象一下
何ができるのかな
我能做些什么
Kono shunkan, kono basho ga sutaato
信じられない出来事だってある
会发生些不可思议的事吧
Imeeji shite miyou nani ga dekiru no ka na
もっと超えて行けるね
克服一切走的更远
Shinjirarenai dekigoto datte aru
ゼロから生まれるすべて輝いて
从零重生的一切都特别耀眼
Motto... koete yukeru ne
FLYあの空へ
翱翔朝着那片天空
Zero kara umareru subete kagayaite ano sora e
思い切り羽ばたきたい
想尽情地展翅
最高のスマイルで笑いながら
以最完美的笑容
さぁ、行く
笑着前行吧
Omoikiri habatakitai
未知の世界へと　今飛び出そうよ
奔向未知的世界仿佛就要飞出来
Saikou no sumairu de warainagara saa yukou!
未来を選び決めるのは自分
自己决定自己的未来
Michi no sekai e to ima tobidasou yo
夢を追いかけて行　こう泣く日をある
追逐着梦想前进　也会有哭泣的日子
それは大事な願い消えないで
珍贵的愿望不会消失
Mirai wo erabi, kimeru no wa jibun
Yume wo oikakete yukou
きっと会えるから
一定可以再次遇
Naku hi mo aru
明日の君
朝着未来的你
Sore wa daiji na negai, kienaide
Kitto aeru kara, asu no kimi e...
"The Devil is a Part-Timer!"
The Hero Enters the Fray
勇者、修羅場に突入する
What? So you've been cooking for
Mr. Ashiya while he has heat fatigue?
じゃ、夏ばてしている
芦屋さんのかわりにお食事を
Now I see!
そうだったんですか
Wow, that perilla is chopped
so thinly! It's really pretty!
紫蘇がこんなに細かく刻まれて
すごく綺麗
It's easy if you slice it in half first,
then gather it in a bunch before you julienne it.
紫蘇半分に切って
重ねて纏めてから戦きりすれば簡単だ
How did you get the lettuce so crisp?
そにレタスチシャしゃきしゃきしているのは
After you give it a good washing,
you just have to shake off the water.
きちんと水にさたしてから
その後水分をふればいい
Really? I'm so impressed, Miss Suzuno!
ええ、鈴乃さん、尊敬します
Sure is crowded in here. Will we
have enough bowls and chopsticks?
人口密度高いな
箸と茶碗足りるか
Oh, I brought mine with me.
私、自分のは持って来ました
Oh. Okay, then I'll accept this with thanks!
そっか、じゃ、ありがたく招待しますか
And Miss Kamazuki helping too...
I'm so sorry for the trouble.
鎌月さんも本当にすみません
Oh, breakfast already?
もう朝ご飯
Wait, where am I supposed to sit?
あれ、僕どこに坐ればいいの
I'll go delinquent on you.
くれて野郎
And why do I rate below Yusa, anyway?!
っていうか、なんで遊佐より扱いがしたなのさ
Guests first.
お客様優先
And these are the bowls
from that Sugiya takeout!
大体これ、この前杉屋の容器じゃないの
Bon appétit!
いただきます
- Bon appétit!
- Hey!
いただきます
おい
Wow, I want to become a
great cook like you, Miss Suzuno.
あたしも鈴乃さんみたいに
お料理うまく乗りたいです
I'm sure you'll progress quickly.
千穂殿はすぐに上達する
You really think so?
本当ですか
As for me, it sounds nice to say
I'm "treating them to home cooking,"
私も手料理をご馳走しているといえば
聞こえはいいが
but really I'm just being pushy and
making them help me use up my noodles.
実際にはお仕えましく食材の消費を手伝わせてだけた
- I bought in bulk to be frugal until I find a job,
- Wait, I thought we had some fried fish?
仕事が見つかるまで食費の節約とはいえ
- but I might not be able to eat
it all before it spoils in the heat.
- Hey, didn't we?
夏ばてこの量がくそがなねない
- What jobs are you considering, by the way?
- I know I saw some. I know I did.
ところで、どんなお仕事を考えているの
- I won't be unreasonable
and ask for a full-time job.
- There was fried fish, right? Come on! Fried fish!
正社員などと贅沢は言わない
- If I can make enough money
- There was, right? Or did I imagine it?
最低限の生活さえどらめる奉公ならば
- to cover minimal living expenses
by going into service, that's enough.
- There was, right? Or did I imagine it?
それでいい
- Who says "going into service" these days?
- There was some, right?
奉公って今時
Why not come to MgRonald's, then?
なら、うちの店くれば
Chi's there too, so you won't have to
be too stressed during your training.
ちーちゃんもいるから
あまり緊張しないで新人研修できるし
Sure, that won't be stressful,
but there'll be otherstress.
いやいや、そっちの緊張がないけど
別の緊張があるでしょう
Lots of shifts are understaffed
lately, so we'd like the help.
最近シュフトすることが多いから人手ほしいし
Anybody'd notice how the
high school girl feels about this!
普通気づくだろう
女子校生の気持ち
Don't you think so, Chi?
ちーちゃんもそう思わん？
Huh?!
ええと、はい
Um... y-yes.
This is hopeless.
ダメだ、こりゃ
Well, no need to make a snap decision!
まぁ、そう性急に決めたことないわよ
There are as many minuses to working
with people you know as there are pluses!
知り合いがいる職場ってのは
メリットと同じくらいデメリットあるものよ
Thank you, good Sadao.
I'll consider it as an option.
ありがとう、貞夫殿
候補の一つと考えて
I may end up asking for help later.
最終的にはお願いするかもしれない
Sure, okay.
まぁ、いいけど
If so, I'll appreciate your help too, good Chiho.
千穂殿もその際にはよろしく頼む
O-Okay...
は、はい
仕事もそうですが
The job is important, but for now,
とりあえず、服装とか持ち物など
why not help her with
her clothes and belongings?
なんとかして上げては如何ですか
True, my dresser is rather bare,
and I lack any purses or shoes.
確かに、私の箪笥の眺めは乏しく
カバンや履物多分いもない
Wait, don't tell me you've only
got traditional Japanese clothes?
まさか、和服しか持ってないわけじゃないわよね
I have no Western-style clothing.
洋服の持ち合わせはない
I-Is there something strange about that?
何かおかしいわ
Well, I don't know about "strange," but...
いや、おかしいということはないんですが
Yusa, you know where
they sell stuff like this, right?
遊佐なら
こういうのはどこかにあるのか知ってんだろう
Hey! No touching without permission!
You'll infect me with NEET-ness!
ちょっと、勝手に触らないでよ
ニートがうつるじゃない
It ain't infectious!
うつるか
相変わらず漆原さんそういうこと平気でするんですね
You never feel any shame about doing
that stuff, do you, Mr. Urushihara?
What's your problem?!
Why is everybody so mean to me?!
何で、何でよ、何で皆僕に冷たいの
Miss Yusa, why don't you take
her to some clothing stores?
遊佐さん、服屋さんとか
案内してあげたら
まぁ、会社終わった後なら
Okay, if we can do it after work...
I'll wander around the shopping
area until you're finished, then.
では、それまでは現地をぶらぶらするとしよう
- Good idea.
- Yeah, good idea!
そうですね
Best not to take the risk, if you ask me...
下手なことしないほうがいいと思うな
Thank you for waiting.
お待たせした
Er...
ええと、それ、着替えだの
Did you just change clothes?
Yes.
本当に和服しか持ってないんだ
She really does only have traditional clothes.
Is something wrong?
何か
No, forget it.
いや、いい
Shall we go?
じゃ、行こうか
All right, sorry to visit so early.
それじゃ、朝早くから
お邪魔しました
Get well soon, Mr. Ashiya.
芦屋さん、お大事にしてくださいね
Thank you for the wonderful food.
こちらこっそ
結構なものをありがとうございます
Now, Sire, you be sure to
escort Miss Sasaki back home.
魔王様
佐々木さんをきちんとお宅まで送りするのですよ
What are you, my old lady?
お前は俺のおふくろか
Your bike...
真奥さんの自転車
Dullahan.
ギラハンゴな
Right. It doesn't have
a carrier on the back, huh?
って、後ろに荷台ないですね
But utility bikes hardly ever do, right?
でも、してサイクルで皆そんなもんだろう
It's kind of a shame.
ちょっと残念
A second rider gets you a fine of up
to 20,000 yen in the city, you know.
都内間二人乗りは二万円以下の罰金だぜ
Of course I know. But that's not my point...
知ってますし
でも、そういうじゃなくて
Say, Chi, didn't your
parents have anything to say
そのさ、ちーちゃんが俺たちみたいな
男の家に来るの
about you visiting a bachelor pad?
ご両親、何か言わないの
Not particularly. I was honest
about where I was going, after all.
別に何も言われませんでしたよ
行き先は正直に話してますし
We've got Mom's approval, as they say!
言うならばお母さん公認です
A-And your dad?
おやじさんは
お父さんは
Dad said, "So, you've already
found a man you want to cook for?"
もう料理を作ってやりたい奴があるのかって
Oh, what are you going to do
for lunch, since Miss Suzuno's out?
今日、鈴乃さん出かけちゃいましたけど
お弁当どうするんですか
Do? Uh, I haven't really thought about it...
どうするって
特に何も考え
なら、もしよかったら
In that case, is it all right if I bring you lunch?
私、お弁当作って来て
いいですか
Well, um... Ashiya would feel better
about me eating your home cooking
まぁ、その、芦屋も俺がジャンクフード
食うよりちーちゃんの
than living on junk food, so...
手作り弁当の方が安心するし
I guess I'll take you up on that.
お言葉に甘えようかな
Yay! I'll have to make sure
it's nutritionally balanced, then,
やった、じゃ芦屋さんが安心できるように
栄養バランス考えて作らなきゃですね
so that he'll feel safe!
Look, Chi... Doesn't it bother you that we're?
ちーちゃん、そのさ
気にならないの
俺達のさ
That you're demons from another world?
遊佐の世界で悪魔だってことか
Well, yeah.
まぁ
True, I'd be lying if I said it didn't bother me.
そうですね
気にならないって言えば
嘘になります
Miss Yusa and I have been texting each other,
遊佐さんとはメールのやり取りしてるんで
so I know a little about what you've done.
真奥さんが何をしたのかも
すごしだけ知ってます
But I fell for you before
I knew about that, Mr. Maou.
でも、そんなこと知る前に
真奥さんのこと
好きになちゃいましたから
Don't make that pathetic face!
Are you really aiming for world conquest?
そんな顔しないでください
本当にそんなで
世界征服目指しているんですか
But it's just...
でも
Miss Yusa tried to stop me, so that I
wouldn't have to regret falling for you.
遊佐さんは私が真央さんに
好きになって後悔しないように
止めてくれたけど
But I fell for you on my own.
私は、自分で真奥好きになったんです
So when I stop liking you,
I'll do that on my own, too.
だから、好きでなくなる時も自分で決めます
Even if you only think of me as your
junior coworker, it's no big deal.
真奥さんが私のことを後輩だとしか思ってなくても
別に何ともありません
Because it doesn't have anything
to do with me liking you.
そんな事と私が真奥さんのことが好きで居るのとは関係ありませんから
Jeez, this is what makes humans so scary.
全くこれだから人間とのは恐ろしいなぁ
そうですよ
That's right!
Especially girls... take us lightly and
you'll wish you'd only been maimed!
特に女の子はなめてると大怪我じゃすみませんからね
I'll keep that in mind.
心しとくよ
You're truly loved, good Sadao.
貞夫殿　愛されてるな
M-M-M-Miss Suzuno!
H-H-How long have you been there?!
すすすすす鈴乃さん　いー何時からそこに？！
Since somewhere around "I fell for you."
真奥さんのこと　好きになっちゃいました あの辺りから
I think you're very virtuous, and cute,
for being so honest about your feelings.
自分に心に素直である千穂殿はとても高潔で可愛らしいと思う
- Regardless of whom you've picked.
- Huh?!
どんな相手であろうと
えっ　ちーちゃん
Chi?!
Aw, jeez. I hope she doesn't get
into an accident going that fast.
ったくもう
あんな勢いで飛び出して事故なきゃいいけど
You surprise me.
意外だ
Is it really so surprising that
I'd worry about somebody?
俺が人の心配するのがそんなに意外か
Apologies, but yes.
失礼ながら人から好意を寄せられることについてどう思う
What are your thoughts on
having a person like you?
Huh? Why the interrogation?
はぁ
何の調査
Oh, there's no deep meaning behind it...
いや　深い意味が無いのだが
Well, let's see. After she was so direct about it,
もう　そうだな
あれだけストレートに来られちゃうんだな
I don't wanna just pretend I don't get it.
こっちとしても、下手に誤魔化しとくもねぇし
Plus, Chi... more like her parents...
well, her mom trusts me,
それに　ちーちゃんがってより、ご両親っていうか
おふくろさんに信用されちゃ
so I figure I gotta show my good faith... Hey!
誠意を見せなきゃならんだろうなぁ
って何だ　その顔
What's with that look?
Oh, no, it's nothing.
いや　何でもない
Ah, that's right, I've kept the good Emi waiting.
あー　そうだ
恵美殿　待たしてるんどと
You're going to the station,
right? I'll walk you there.
駅まで来るんだろう
送るよ
えっ
Wh-What?
な　何
No... nothing...
いや　何でもない
"Sasazuka Station"
Find your wallet?
財布あった
Y-Yeah, I'm okay.
I've kept you waiting; I'm sorry.
あっあー　大丈夫だ
待たせたようだ　済まない
Oh, no big deal.
良いわよ　別に
Er, so are we about to ride
what they call a "train"?
えっとこれから　電車っとやらに乗るのか
Well, yes. We're only one stop from
Shinjuku, but it's a bit far to walk.
そうね
新宿までは一駅だけど　歩くにはちょっと遠いしね
Yes, about that... I've never been on a train.
そのことなんだが
実は　私は電車に乗ったことがない
Huh?
えっ
I've heard that in Tokyo one
pays for travel in watermelons.
【是铃乃将两个同音词听错了】
東京ではスイカを通行カードだと聞いているのだが
Where can I obtain one?
どこで入手するのがよいのか
U-Um, wait a second.
Can I ask you something first?
えっと　ちょっと待って
その前に　聞いてもいい
How the heck did you get to Sasazuka?
一体どうやって笹塚まで来たの
I came here directly through the Gate.
私はゲートを使って　直接笹塚に降りたんだが
Oh, that explains...
あー　そういう
Did you just say "Gate"?
今　ゲートって言った
Are you... from Ente Isla?
貴方　エンテイスラから来たの
Wait, didn't you know that?
気づいていたのではないのか
Huh?!
えええええええええ
"Sasazuka Station"
You didn't say a word about that!
そんな事一言も言わなかったじゃない
You did! You asked if I was after the Devil!
貴方から言ったではないか
魔王狙っているのかっと
And then you told me it would
end badly if I got close to him,
その後　貴方は魔王に近づけば不幸になる
and as a favor you warned me to steer clear!
浮かずにに近づくなっと忠告してくれただろう
Huh?!
えっ
So even though I've survived countless wars,
私もこれで数々と修羅場くぐり抜けている身だが
I knew I had to withdraw because you,
the hero, rated him so dangerous!
勇者である貴方に言われては聞かざる終えない
But when I asked for help because I had
nowhere to go if I left right away,
だがすぐあそこに行き払っても行く当てがないんで
助力を願ったら
you pledged your aid and gave
me your contact information!
貴方は協力を約束して連絡先を教えてくれたではないか
What?!
ええええええええ
Didn't you say those nice things
because you intuited who I was?!
私の正体を察して会いに来たではないのか
How could I possibly intuit that?!
どう察すれば貴方の正体に気づけるのよ
Didn't it strike you as odd?!
可笑しいとは思わなかったのか
A sweet young girl such as
myself who just moved in,
引っ越したばかりの私のような幼気の少女
- Who calls herself that?!
- venturing into an all-male home and
slaving away for them? It's ridiculous!
自分でさえ言う
男とこに乗り込んで甲斐甲斐しく世話をやるのは
有り得ないだろう
Hearing that from you is seriously irritating!
あなたにそう言われるとすごく腹ただしいいわ
Then what exactly were you thinking
when you asked me if I was "after" him?!
じゃぁ　一体どういうつもりで魔王狙っているのかってなど聞いていたのだ
Huh? Wait... Wh-Why did you ask if I had
a"very close" relationship with him?
貴方こそ
どういうつもりで魔王と親密な
付き合いをしているのかあとか聞いてるのよ
Because I was told you'd joined forces with him!
貴方が魔王と共同しているという情報があったからだ
じょっ　冗談じゃないわよ
Th-That's a load of crap!
We were just forced to take down
偶然共通な敵を仕方なく一緒に倒すために陥っただけで
a coincidentally shared
enemy together, that's all!
So don't talk like that, it's just stupid!
共同ってなんて馬鹿なこと言わないで
Don't tell me you actually thought
I was conspiring with the Devil
まさか　私が魔王とけいたくして
教会へ復讐を企んでも思ったわけ
to get revenge on the Church?!
It was you who sneak-attacked the
convenience store yesterday, wasn't it?
やっぱり昨日コンビニで襲ってきたのは貴方ね
Kelp
Perilla
and
Kelp
Cod
Roe
and
Kelp
【这姑娘把便利店和袭击两个词听错了】
昆布にでお惣菜
Seaweed snacked?
Dried Kelp
Grrr!
I got attacked by someone from Ente Isla.
エンテイスラから来たやつに襲われたのよ
They had the power to neutralize my
sacred sword, so they weren't a demon.
聖剣を無効化する力を持ってたから　悪魔じゃない
Which means it had to have been you...
となれば　貴方しかいない
Huh?
あっあれ
She doesn't have any paintball
marks, and she doesn't smell!
ペイントボールの痕跡も匂いもない
I did no such thing! I know
how powerful the hero Emilia is!
私はそんなことはしていない
勇者エミリアの実力は知っている
Who are you, then, and why are you
hanging around the Devil's Castle?
じゃ　貴方は何処の誰で　どうして魔王城に入り浸ってるの
My real name is Crestia Bel.
I'm head investigator of the
Doctrinal Correction Council.
If you still intend to defeat Satan, join us and...
Wait!
まって　会社に遅刻したくないから
I don't want to be late for work,
so save the details for Shinjuku, okay?
詳しい話は新宿についたからね
あ
This is just how Japan works.
日本ってそういう国なの
離せ　私はここで立ち止まるわけには
Release me! I-I cannot afford to dawdle here!
Do you insist on hindering me?!
あくまで私の邪魔をする気か
ああああああ
"Shinjuku Station"
I can't believe you actually said
"There are people inside this little panel!"
まさかテレビを見て
「薄板の中に人が」なんてセリフ本当に言うとは思わなかった
when you saw a flat screen TV.
Please, let's drop that subject!
そんな話はもうやめてくれ
How the heck did you study Japan, anyway?
一体貴方何を見て日本を勉強したの
After I realized yukata and kimono
were the traditional Japanese dress,
和服は日本の伝統衣装だと分かったから
一番和服が出る時代劇というものを選んだ
I studied something called "historical
drama," which features the most kimono.
And also a documentary on the Showa
period, the longest era in modern Japan.
後は近代日本で一番長い時間続いた昭和のドキュメンタリーだ
Now I see.
なるほど
My favorites are O-arashi Monjiro,
Lone Lion and Cub,
特に気に入ってるのは「大嵐紋次郎」や「子連れ獅子」に
and ronin shows like Three for the Slay!
後は「三匹刈り」のような浪人者だな
「水戸副将軍」や「怒りん坊将軍」などはあまり欣然に響かなかった
Things like Mito Fukushogun and
Okorinbo Shogun didn't really resonate.
Uh-huh... So, getting back on topic,
あっそう
で　話を元に戻すと
why did the Doctrinal Correction
Council's head investigator
訂教審議会の筆頭審問官さんがどういうつもりで魔王城の隣に
move next door to the Devil's Castle?
All I learned from investigating Olba Mayer
オルバメーヤの痕跡を調査して分かったのは
was where Satan lived and
what sort of lifestyle he had.
魔王がどこでどういう暮らしをしているかということだけだった
I thought if I kept tabs on the Devil...
だから魔王を見張っていれば何れ勇者が現れるとっ
...the hero would eventually show up.
So, what did you want with me?
で　私に何の用
First let me say one thing.
その前にこれだけは言わせて欲しい
I cannot apologize enough for
Olba Mayer's immoral acts against you.
貴方に対してオルバメーヤが行った不義に対しては　おわびの仕様もない
From your attitude toward me
before you knew I was Ente Islan,
私をエンテイスラ人　知らずに見せた態度を見れば
I can see that the story of you joining
the Devil was probably incorrect.
貴方が魔王と共同しているという話も間違いなのだろうと分かる
Olba's will is not the Church's collective will.
彼の意志が教会の総意ではない
I, at least, would like to be on your side.
少なくとも私は貴方の見方で有りたいと思っている
Olba isn't important now. Let's cut to the chase.
そのことはもういいの　本題は
I want you to take down King Satan
with me, and then return to Ente Isla.
私と一緒に魔王サタンを倒し
エンテイスラに戻って欲しい
The Church would make your survival
known, but cover up Olba's wrongdoing.
貴方の生存を知らしめて
オルバの不正を隠そうとする教会を正しくもらえないか
Will you set them straight?
No way.
嫌よ
I'm trying to restore your
proper status and honor here!
貴方の地位と名誉をあるべき姿に戻そうというのだぞ
I don't particularly care what the
Church or the kingdoms think of me.
別に教会や諸国にどう思われてようと気にしないわ
But I'm sure you can understand why
I can't just up and trust someone
だけど　大勢の人がいた地下道を
私と魔王を殺すためだけに崩落させたやつが
from an organization
led in part by the same guy
最高責任者を務めいたところからきましたって貴方を
who caved in a crowded underground mall
just to kill me and the Devil.
「はい　そうですか」って素直に信じられないのは分かるわよね
Emerada and Albert could
tell you how much trouble
オルバが私を殺すためにルシベルと一緒にさんざんこの国に迷惑をかけたことは
Olba caused this country with
Lucifer in order to kill me.
ェメレダやアルバートも知ってることよ
Or you can ask Urushihara himself.
漆原本人に聞いてみてもいい
Besides... taking down the
Devil is my job as a hero.
それに
魔王を倒すのは勇者である私の役目よ
Don't interfere.
手を出さないで
Then if we cooper...
ならばお互いに協力す。。。
The old Inquisition, now known as
the "Doctrinal Correction Council."
一旦審問会改めて
今は提供審議会だったわね
You're with them, and you still don't get it?
そこの人間の人の癖に分からないよ
Oh, and I don't know why
you're giving them food aid,
それと
何のつもりであいつらに食料援助してるか知らないけど
but I'll warn you of one thing:
一応警告しておくわ
if you mess with him or play any cheap
tricks, he'll see right through you.
つまらない小細工や下手なちょっかい出すと
すぐにカンパされるわよ
He may not look it, but he is the Devil.
あれでも魔王ですからね
I... appreciate your warning.
忠告痛み入る
Still, you've got your own
position to think about, right?
どういっても
あなたにはあなたの都合があるもんね
I grabbed this at the station
for you. And this, too.
これ
さっき駅で取ってきたから
"Jobs Worth Doing"
それとこれも
I grabbed this at the station
for you. And this, too.
"Find Your Perfect Job"
If you're going to be here a while,
learn a little more about the place.
しばらくこっちにいるんだったら
この世界のことも
もう少し勉強しなさい
The way you dress and talk
is just way too old-fashioned.
そのスタイルや言葉遣い
いくらなんでも時代がかりすぎよ
Okay, I have to go to work now.
Let's save the rest for after my shift.
じゃ　あたしこれから仕事だから
後は会社が終わってからしましょう
すいませんでした
I'm so sorry!
F-For what?
っあ　何が
I-I... stole your bike...
自転車　勝手に
Oh, that.
ああ　そっちね
- I'm sorry! I'm sorry! I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
- No, it's okay. It's okay!
すいません！すいません!すいません！。。。
いや　いいっていいって！
It's as slow here today as I figured.
やっぱ今日は客少ねーな
The new SFC across the
street took all our customers.
向かいにできたセンタッキーに全部持って変えてるよ
And Miss Kisaki's got a super
dangerous smile on her face...
それに木崎さんスゲーやばい何ですけど
I'm skiin' without a jacket.
Our sales've dropped over 80% since yesterday.
前日比が80%割っている
Why do I have to go to headquarters today?
なぜこんな日がから本社に行かねばならんのだ
ああ。。。
Once, somebody hired in my year
lost a fierce competition with her rival
私の動機にはライバルとの私立の戦いに破る
and got packed off to Greenland.
グリーンランドに飛ばされるのもいる
For real?
マジっすか？！
No way do we want to go to Greenland, right?
グリーンランド行きは嫌だよな
Right!
はい！
I don't care what you have to do.
I authorize any means necessary!
私が許可する
どんな手を使ってもかまわん
Defeat SFC!
センタッキーを倒せ！
Yes, Ma'am!
yes,ma'am!
"Sentucky"
ああ　参ったな
Dang it! I can't believe this is my
first day as substitute manager...
店長代理生に叱るこれじゃ
Welcome!
いらっしゃいませ
Excuse me, I know you're busy.
お忙しいところ失礼します
Is the manager here?
店長さんはいらっしゃいますか
申し訳ございません
I'm sorry, but Manager Kisaki isn't here today.
店長に木崎は本日不在でして
I'd be happy to assist you in her place.
よろしければ私が用件が承りますが
Sadao Maou, I presume?
I've heard a lot about you.
あなたが真奥貞夫さんですか？
うわさがかねがね
Hardworking, sociable, and broad-minded...
勤勉さ　社交性　応用力
I hear you have a wonderful
human touch in everything.
どれをとっても非常に人間见あふれる方だと
Er, I'm flattered.
は。。。恐れ入ります
Does this guy need help?
困った人なのか
Oh dear, excuse me. Here is my card.
もっと失礼　私　こういうものでございます
Oh, thank you.
ああ　どうも
The manager of Sentucky Fried Chicken?!
さんたっキーフライドチキンの店長さん？！
The name is Mitsuki Sarue. I'm sorry
for not coming to greet you sooner.
猿江三月と申します
ご挨拶が遅れて申し訳ない
I've been so busy, you see.
何せ忙しくて
I have to say, Hatagaya is a nice neighborhood.
それにしても幡ヶ谷がいい町ですね
It's right between the residential and business
areas, so the demographics are excellent.
住宅地とビジネス街の挟間で客層が豊か
All the women are gorgeous.
女性はみな美しい
Right.
そっすね
Well, let's do our best as fellow
workers in the station shopping arcade.
駅前商店街の仲間として
お互い頑張りましょう
Hmm.
うん～
Well! It's a shame I can't see your
famously ravishing manager, bu... what?!
うわさの美人過ぎる店長を
目にかからなかったら残念ですっわ！
Gorgeous.
美しい
Please, use those graceful hands of yours
ぜひ　あなたのそのたおやかな手で
to make a to-go meal just for me...
私のためだけにお持ち帰りのセットを
つくっていただきたい
...my young lady.
お嬢さん～
Sorry, Chi. I should've
put a stop to that creeper.
千ちゃん悪い
あのナンパ紛いは俺が止めるべきだったのに
No, Mr. Maou, it wasn't your fault!
別に真奥さんのせいじゃありません
I'm just disgusted with that
little shrimp of a manager!
あのちび小店長にむかむかとしただけです
Heavy cologne and sunglasses? I question
that in a customer service worker!
きつい香水それにサングラス
サービス業として
どうかと思えません
I'm not going to lose to him!
絶対向きません
- That's the spirit.
- Huh?
その生きだ
We'll have info on the enemy soon. I sent in a spy.
近々敵情報が入ってクサを払ったからな
くさ？
A spy?
As my king bids it,
魔王様の王政とあらば
I shall thoroughly investigate that
"Sentucky Fried Chicken" place!
このアシア
そのセンタッキーフライドチキンとやら
徹底的に調査させていただきます
- Boy, I'm starving!
- Good Emi.
もうお腹すいたね
エミ殿
Good Emi, you've finished your service at last?
エミ殿　ようやく方向を得られたが
So you ended up buying more yukata...
結局和服買っちゃったのね
Did you have that much money?
お金そんなにもってたの
I had some easily converted assets,
so I sold a few at a shop called Mugihyo.
換金率の高いものを持っていたので
いくつかという麦兵店で買い取ってもらった
Th-Th-This is!
ここここれは0　0。。。
I just hope you didn't sell
any valuables for a song...
貴重なものを捨て値で手放してなければいいんだけど
I managed to buy it! Impressed?
どうだ？
ちゃんと買えたぞ
Um...
ええと
Please enter your payment,
making sure to check the amount.
金額を引き出しの上
お金入れてください
"OK"
If you require a receipt,
please press the receipt button.
領収書の必要の方は領収書ボタンを押してください
Wh-What more do you want?!
こ、この上何を
Great job, kid.
偉い偉い
Say, is this a friend of yours?
あのう　こちらエミのお友達？
Um, well, I guess you could say that...
ええっと　まあそういうことになるのかな
I waited here because I have
another request for you, good Emi.
ここで待っていたのは
エミ殿にお願いがあって
What is it?
何？
I wish to go see the good Sadao's workplace.
貞夫殿の職場を見に行きたいんだ
- Would you accompany me?
- H-H-Hey!
一緒に行ってくれまいか
ちょっと
"Sadao"? I feel like I know that name...
貞夫？
聞いたことがあるような
- I know you don't want me getting close to him,
- Whoa, hey!
私を彼に近づけたくないのは分かるが
but I can't just stand down.
私を引き下がる分けには行かない
Huh? What does she mean? Hey, what's up?
ええ?何それ？
ああ　ほら　困った
- Did I stumble into a bloodbath here?!
- I knew this would happen...
Hey, I know I'm butting in here, but you
usually can't resolve these things alone!
あんたさ
おせっかいだったことは分かってるんだけどさ
こういう場合基本的にワンサイトじゃ解決しないよ
- You need a third party to
be the judge, you know?!
- I'm telling you, Rika, it's not like that!
第三者。。。
だったら里香そんなんじゃない
You need help. I'll tag along!
仕方ないな
付き合うよ
So, where is this Mr. Sadao?
で　貞夫氏どこいるの？
At the Hatagaya MgRonald's...
幡ヶ谷のマグドナルドだが
- Hey, w-wait!
- Aw, we can get there by train in no time!
へえ　電車で　すぐじゃん
ちょ、ちょっと
I'm not going, got it?!
私は行かないだよね
"Sasahata Tanabata Festival"
一二三四
Doko kara asa ni naru? Shizuka na sora
どこから朝になる
从何处开始是清晨
静かな空
安静的天空
Minai furi wo shita yubikiri koyubi no saki
見ないふりをした指きり
装作没看见的拉钩
恋日の先笑われた
恋爱之前被嘲笑
Warawareta tsuki nara kiete
yuku n da kinou no houkaku e
つきなら  消えてゆくんだ
就算是月亮 也会要消失
昨日の方角
向着昨天的方向
うそつき　臆病者
胆小的人　说谎精
Usotsuki okubyoumono
minna matomete boku nara
みんなまとめて　  僕なら　最低言ったのは
大家总结的这些　　我的话   就说声差劲
Saite ita no wa yume no naka da
夢の中だ
在梦中
月の影に隠してた
藏在月影中
Tsuki no kage ni kakushiteta
hontou wa ne naiteta
本当はね　泣いていだ
其实正在哭泣
Namida wa mou nagarenai karete shimatta no?
涙はもう流れない
眼泪已经不再流
枯れてしまうたな
枯竭了吧
Nani mo ka mo yurusetara
nagareru ka mo shirenai kedo
何もかも許せたら
虽然什么都原谅的话
流れるかもしれないけど
眼泪可能还是会流出来
Mamoritai mono bakari da na
守りたいものばかりだなあ
全都是想要守护的东西
The Hero Experiences a Fray